Aimee Knight

Full Stack Engineer
170 Plum Nelly Circle
Brentwood, TN 37027
(205) 913-4533
AimeeMarieKnight@gmail.com
AimeeMarieKnight.com

Objective

I'm passionately curious about emerging technology, while solidly focused on fundamental principles. As a former professional figure skater, I'm extremely driven, holding myself and the software I write to the highest standards. I enjoy staying active in the JavaScript community through speaking on podcasts, and helping organize meetups and conferences.

While much of the code I write for my employer is private, my open source software projects can be found on GitHub.

Current Summary

DramaFever (NYC, NY/Remote)

Front End Software Engineer, 2016-Present

As a front end software engineer at DramaFever, I've worked in a rapidly paced environment building out features for <u>Boomerang</u>, <u>Warner Archive</u>, <u>Moodica</u>, and <u>DramaFever</u> using Angular.js and Django. While at DramaFever, I have been especially focused on preparring our code base for the lastest version of Angular by following a component model, and driving adoption of the lastest version of JavaScript by leading weekly internal training sessions.

Strengths include:

- Test-driven development
- Designing/Writing Front End UI's with Angular.js and React.js
- Designing/Writing APIs with Node.js
- Staying up to date with the latest technologies and libraries
- Mentoring
- CSS

JavaScript Jabber & Angular Air

Panelist, 2015-Present

 Interview community leaders about various open source projects, and other popular JavaScript and Angular topics.

Experience

Kuali (Lehi, UT/Remote)

Full-Stack Software Engineer, 2016

- Built out features for a higher education curriculum management system using React.js, Redux, and Node.js with Express and Koa.
- Increasing products reliability and stability by helping to drive adoption of front end test with Enzyme and increasing back end test coverage.
- Helped implement the latest technologies within code base including WebPack, Flow, ES6 and ES7.

Message Systems (Columbia, MD)

Full-Stack Software Engineer, 2014-2016

- Built out features for the core on-premise solution, and cloud offering, <u>SparkPost</u> utilizing Angular.js and Node.js.
- Led migration to ES6 and the official AngularJS style guide.
- Preparred UI for Angular 2.
- Maintained 100% front end and back end test coverage.

Nashville Software School (Nashville, TN)

Apprentice - Advanced Alpha Group, 2014-2015

Completed a six-month intensive, full-time, hands-on, fast-moving and rigorous study of software engineering. Emphasis was placed on building database driven applications, and working with other students while immersed in new and challenging material.

Highlights include: - Computer Science fundamentals, algorithms, operating systems and security - Test-driven development with Rspec & Mocha - Ruby * Ruby on Rails with SQLite and PostgreSQL - JavaScript & Node.js with MongoDB - Agile software development & pair-programming

Boost by Design LLC. (Richmond Hill, GA)

Junior Web Developer, 2013-2014

- Implement theme modifications for cross-browser support from completed Photoshop design files while maintaining W3C compliance.
- Utilize a mobile first design approach, implementing media queries for all standard breakpoints.
- Address issues with broken themes as well as hosting account configuration.
- Educate clients on Wordpress CMS, SEO, and accessibility best practices.
- Work within tight deadlines to satisfy urgent client requests.

Fast Forward Video Inc. (Irvine, CA)

Sales and Marketing Administrator, 2012

Manage global customer base including and serve as primary Salesfore (CRM) administrator.

Restore Therapy Services Ltd. & Comfort Care Home Health and Hospice LLC. (Birmingham, AL)

Business Development Coordinator, 2009-2010

- Responsible for overseeing production Web Sites, SEO, and additional marketing material.
- Work with prospects, CEO and Director of Business Development to implement new contracts.

FitzMartin Inc. (Birmingham, AL)

Project Manager/Junior Account Manager, 2007-2009

- Collaborate with Software Developers, Creatives, and Account Executives to ensure projects deadlines are met on time and on budget.
- Set up production schedules for all projects in order to maintain critical path management for an average of 110 jobs per week.

City of Pelham - Pelham Civic Complex (Pelham, AL)

Private Figure Skating Coach, 2000-2007

Instruct all ages and all levels in various disciplines of Figure Skating.

Education

- Nashville Software School Student / Apprentice Advanced Alpha Group, 2014-2015
- University of Massachusetts at Lowell Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, 2012-Present
- University of Alabama at Birmingham Summa Cum Laude Bachelor of Arts in Communication Management & Mass Communications, 2002-2007

Skills

- HTML5, Jade & Haml
- CSS3, Less & Sass
- Javascript (Including ES6) & jQuery
- Angular.js, React.js & Redux
- Ruby/Rails with Rspec
- Django
- Node.js/Express.js with Mocha
- Protractor & Selenium
- SQLite, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RethinkDB, ElasticSearch
- Grunt & Gulp
- Vim
- Git
- Amazon Web Services
- TravisCI, Coveralls, & Gemnasium
- Wordpress Theme Development
- Basic Adobe Photoshop and InDesign

References

References are available upon request.